jwu.edu 2005-04-03

# J&W legal | website privacy policy

legal notices

| 

**Johnson & Wales University Website Privacy Policy**

**Introduction**  
It is the intent of Johnson & Wales University and its affiliates and agents ("JWU", "the University", "we" or "our") to comply in all material respects with all applicable privacy laws and, we are strongly committed to respecting and protecting your privacy. This Johnson & Wales University Privacy Policy ("Policy") applies to information that is collected through the website located at www.jwu.edu ("Site"). Please carefully read this Policy before using the Site and providing any Information (defined below) through the Site.

**User Consent to Privacy Policy**  
Any person accessing, browsing, or otherwise using the Site, either manually or via an automated device or program, shall be considered a "User." All Users are bound by the terms of this Policy. Users consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of personally identifiable User information and anonymous browsing information (collectively "Information") to the extent not prohibited by law. If you do not consent to this Policy, please do not access, browse, or use this Site. If you are more comfortable communicating with the University offline, feel free to contact us by mail or telephone using the contact information below.

**The Information JWU Collects**

**Anonymous Browsing Information** Users can browse the Site without revealing personally identifiable information, but anonymous browsing information may be collected. For example, our servers may collect anonymous browsing information, including your Internet Protocol address, your computer’s operating system, the website you came from, and the name of the domain you used to access the Internet.

**Personal Information** JWU collects personal information from Users who voluntary provide such information through the Site in connection with numerous services and activities on the Site. For example, Users are permitted to complete an online application for enrollment in University programs, register for special campus events or programs, make a pledge to the University, purchase merchandise, request more information from the University, communicate with numerous University employees via email and other mediums and take advantage of many other services through the Site. This list is not exhaustive as the University may collect personal information for other purposes and uses when a User provides such Information.

In order to provide these services, JWU collects a variety of personal information, which may include, but is not limited to the following: name, mailing address, date of birth, gender, social security number, email address, telephone and fax numbers, credit card number, educational background, employer name, religious information and citizenship.

**Disclosure of Information to Third Parties**  
JWU may share Information that it collects or receives regarding its Users with third parties as required or permitted by law. In most circumstances though, Information is shared only at the request of a User or to process a request for a User or to provide a service to a User.

JWU also complies with the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which prohibits the release of education records without student permission.

**Linked Internet Websites**  
The Site may provide hyperlinks, which are highlighted words or pictures within a hypertext document that, when clicked, take you to another place within the document, to another document altogether, or may take you to a third party website not controlled by JWU. These hyperlinked third party websites may collect, use and disclose Information different than this Site. JWU is not responsible for the collection, use, or disclosure of information collected through these web sites, and JWU expressly disclaims any and all liability related to such collection, use, or disclosure.

**Children**  
The Site is not directed towards children under 13 years of age and JWU does not knowingly collect any information from children under 13 years of age through the Site. If you are under 13 years of age, you are not permitted to submit personal information to JWU through the Site.

**Security**  
This Site has security measures to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the Information under our control. Unfortunately, no system is perfect; therefore, JWU makes no representations or warranties with regard to the sufficiency of these security measures. JWU shall not be responsible for any actual or consequential damages that result from a lapse in compliance with this Policy because of a security breach or technical malfunction.

**Applicable Law/International Issues**  
Information that is submitted to this Site will be collected, processed, stored, disclosed and disposed of in accordance with applicable U.S. law. If you are a non-U.S. User, you acknowledge and agree that JWU may collect and use your Information, as discussed in this Policy, outside your resident jurisdiction. In addition, such Information may be stored on servers located outside your resident jurisdiction. U.S. law may not provide the degree of protection for Information that is available in other countries. By providing JWU with your Information, you acknowledge that your have read this Policy, understand it, agree to its terms and consent to the transfer of such Information outside your resident jurisdiction. If you do not consent to the terms of this Policy, please do not use this Site, but if you have already provided us with Information, please contact us at [thewebteam@jwu.edu](mailto:thewebteam@jwu.edu) and let us know how you would like us to handle such information.

**Amendments to Policy**  
JWU reserves the right to amend this Policy periodically. Any amendments made to this Policy will be considered effective immediately after the amended Policy is posted on the Site.

**Contact Information**  
If Users have any questions about our services, programs, the Site or this Policy, please contact [thewebteam@jwu.edu](mailto:thewebteam@jwu.edu).

Effective August 23, 2004

back to top

* * *

© 2000-2004 Johnson & Wales University. All rights reserved.
